Cool, so we've hit the ground running now.
We have our running
animation setup, we have
a jumping animation, so we
can fly through the air so excited.
Now we just need to add one more thing, which
is whenever we collide with one of these
barriers, we're not just going to
keep running into one of the barriers.
So what we can do is we can use one
of our other layers for character deaths.
Now in our deaths layer, you can see all of
the different kinds of states that they can
go through, so we can
go from alive to a death
one, so let's see if we double click that,
and we'll see we'll play that, see how that
looks, falls over, and
then death one is just
the character falling over, death
two, what does this one look like?
falls over in front, so falling
over front doesn't really make
any sense in this case, so we'll
probably just go with death one.
Now let's see how we can actually make
this death animation play when it happens.
So let's see the
transitions here, so let's see
the conditions are, so
the death bull should
be set to true, and there's a death
type integer that's equal to one.
So as a good way to
kind of manage the state,
we can actually see
the second transition,
and you can see death type
becomes equal to two in that case.
So since we want the first death animation,
that's the one that we'll go with.
So if we go into our scripts
again, all the way down
at the bottom here, go to
our player controller script.
So now in our player controller script,
we're going to go to the place where we end
the game, where we have
that game over, bit of code.
So down in our on
collision enter, you can
see if we collide with an
obstacle, then the game is over.
So this seems like a
pretty good place where
we can actually make
this death animation occur.
So let's see what kind of methods
we have for our player animator.
So let's see.
So we had set trigger to set a trigger.
Now that death b was a
bull, so can we set bull?
Oh, cool, perfect.
So we'll set bull, and we wanted
the death bull to be true, so let's see.
We can use an int id or
we can use the string name.
So I believe the name was
capital d f underscore b for the bull.
And then the value that we want to set
it to, so in this case, we set it to true.
Cool.
So now we set death
to true, but we need to
actually make sure that we
select the proper death type.
So let's see if we can actually set that
to, so player anim, and then let's see.
So it was an integer, so there's a set
integer option to, so we'll select that one.
And I believe to probably use a string
again, just double check, string name.
So then it was, believe
it was a capital d f
capital t type, and
then an underscore int.
And then I believe the one that
we wanted was the first one, so one.
So now if we save,
so hopefully if we typed
everything properly,
and we set the proper
values, it should, when
we go into our game, cool.
So when we play, let's
see what happens when
we run into the obstacle,
wait for one of them to spawn.
Oh, there they go,
and falls over, and then
it goes into the dead
state in our animation.
So perfect.
So now what you're
going to do to add in this
animation is in your
player controller script,
in our on collision
enter method, where we
actually collide with an
obstacle to end our game.
That's where we're going to
use our player animator variable.
And we're going to set the
animation to be our death be.
And since our death
be is a Boolean, we use
set bool to set it to
true for our death type,
because it's an integer, we set it with
integer, and we'll set that one to one.
So then when we go
play the game, you can
watch as the animator
window transitions when
the player hits one of the obstacles.